EMILY PARKES

Software Developer

NZ Citizen

EXPERIENCE

LEAD BOOTCAMP FACILITATOR | WELLINGTON

Dev Academy Aotearoa

May 2021 - July 2023

- Shown effective communication of complex technical concepts by conveying concepts in a clear and concise manner, while adapting communication style to accommodate individuals with varying levels of technical expertise
- Demonstrated tech awareness and rapid implementation by actively learning and implementing new and other tech into personal projects. Additionally, effectively integrating these new technologies into curriculum exercises tailored to accommodate diverse learning backgrounds ensuring comprehension
- Displayed leadership while guiding and mentoring large cohorts of tech students, inspiring and motivating them to reach their full potential. Led by example and encouraged students to take ownership of their learning and personal growth, fostering a culture of empowerment and self-improvement

BOOTCAMP FACILITATOR | AUCKLAND

Dev Academy Aotearoa

March 2018 - May 2021

- Demonstrated efficient problem solving as a tech newcomer with the ability to identify code issues and swiftly devise solutions, while adapting them to align with students' problem-solving approaches. Simultaneously, honed personal technical expertise through this process
- Displayed the ability to give constructive and actionable feedback in a supportive and motivating manner through staff and student one on one conversations, fostering the continuous growth and development of others. Open to receiving feedback for my own growth and improvement, recognizing its value in personal and professional advancement
- Effectively adapted a specifically designed in-person course into a
 fully online format, while upholding high support, interactive
 activities, and peer coding experiences. Adapted the curriculum
 and devised new processes and tools (such as using Discord,
 Zoom, Miro and VSCode Live Share) to accommodate the diverse
 home and internet setups of participants, ensuring optimal
 engagement and inclusivity throughout the learning process

CONTACT



On request



On request



emilyparkes.me



linkedin.com/emilycocoparkes



github.com/emilyparkes

SUMMARY

For the past 5 years I've been a Facilitator at Dev Academy Aotearoa in Wellington,
Auckland and remote spaces mentoring over
400 students as a Fullstack Developer. I'm
now looking for new opportunities where I
can further develop and expand my skill set
as a Developer.

I am passionate about being creative and have a keen interest in accessibility and projects that have a positive impact on people's lives.

I have a curiosity and love for growth as well as sharing knowledge with others. I am continuously learning skills in both my professional and personal life that help me be creative and think differently.

TECH

- Frontend applications using React and Vite/Webpack
- Clientside state management using Redux
- CSS and Frameworks
- Deployment with Vercel, Dokku, Heroku
- Authentication with Auth0 and a company made module
- Serverside database planning with query builders
- Node serverside with Express
- Used GitHub Actions to automate build, test, and deployment pipelines

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

EXTENDED TRAVEL

May - June 2017

- Traveled to The Netherlands, Spain, United Arab Emirates, Singapore
- Arrived back in New Zealand to prepare for studying at Dev Academy Aotearoa

PRODUCTION MANAGEMENT | VARIOUS FIXED TERM CONTRACTS

Contracts with Screentime, Warner Bros. Entertainment, SKY TV. MediaWorks NZ and others

2015-2017

- Thrived in a high-pressure environment that required effective communication with production zones, the audience, and the venue team to accommodate unpredictable changes in timings
- Thrived in a dynamic environment with changing priorities, relying on effective communication and quick decision-making
- Engaged with the public to maintain high spirits and enforce health and safety standards during crew filming
- Produced daily and weekly reports and provided administration support
- Gained valuable insights into the interdepartmental collaboration and the impact of production teams on various departments and applied improvements

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE IN APPLIED SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Dev Academy Aotearoa

August 2017 - March 2018

DIPLOMA IN PRODUCTION MANAGEMENT

South Seas Film & Television School (now absorbed by Yoobee Collages)

2015

PROJECT

KILN-IT

Using fullstack technologies I have learned and mentor others in (such as React, Typescript and Redux) as well as being a project to try out new tech in more complex scenarios.

I have worked on this project intermittantly while mentoring a Dev Academy Aotearoa.

Currently in the process of converting to Typescript from JavaScript.

View the project on GitHub

INTERESTS

PERSONAL CONTEXT

I enjoy many creative hobbies that allow me to think differently.

- sewing
- · crochet & knitting
- reading
- pottery
- abstract art
- dogs like a lot
- · an average cook that loves food

AWARD

MAATARIKI AWARD OF KINDNESS

Dev Academy Aotearoa | June 2022 Awarded by my peers and management for supporting my colleagues in their roles, during covid 19 and generally being a empowering and supportive colleague